No longer needed?
ไม่ต้องการแล้วเหรอ
What do you mean by that, Mr. Schuwald?
หมายความว่าไงน่ะครับ คุณชูวาลด์
I'm saying that the investigation I asked you to do is now over.
ผมจะบอกว่าเรื่องที่ผมขอให้คุณสืบมันจบแล้ว
Hold on a second.
เดี๋ยวนะครับ
Yes, the investigation on Karl Neuman is done.
จริงอยู่ การสืบสวนเรื่องคาร์ล น็อยมันน่ะจบแล้ว
He was your son.
เขาเป็นลูกชายคุณ
You have my gratitude.
ผมขอบคุณคุณมาก
Wait, hold on.
เดี๋ยวก่อนสิครับ
That doesn't mean everything is resolved.
นี่ไม่ได้แปลว่าทุกอย่างคลี่คลายแล้วนะครับ
There's a possibility that Edmund Fahren did not die by suicide.
มีความเป็นไปได้ว่า เอ็ดมุนด์ ฟาห์เรนไม่ได้ฆ่าตัวตาย
We don't know who was pulling the strings behind Fahren.
เราไม่รู้ว่าใครเป็นคนชักใยอยู่เบื้องหลังฟาห์เรน
Everything has been resolved.
ทุกอย่างคลี่คลายแล้วละ
The tea is ready, Father.
ชาพร้อมดื่มแล้วครับ พ่อ
Oh, I see.
อ๋อ โอเค
Oh, hello.
อ้าว สวัสดีครับ
Would you like some too?
อยากดื่มชาด้วยไหม
Oh no, I'm fine.
ไม่ละครับ ไม่เป็นไร
Thank you for everything.
ขอบคุณสำหรับทุกอย่างนะ
Send me your bill.
ส่งบิลมาเก็บเงินได้เลย
What nice weather today.
วันนี้อากาศดีนะครับ
Yes.
ใช่
Johan is here too.
โยฮันก็มาที่นี่นะครับ
I see. Johan is also here?
อ้อเหรอ โยฮันก็มาด้วยงั้นเหรอ
Can a cold-hearted man who trusts no one and keeps everyone at a distance
ผู้ชายที่เย็นชา ไม่เคยไว้ใจใคร และอยู่ห่างจากทุกคน
transform into a good-natured old man just from finding his son?
กลายเป็นคนแก่ใจดี แค่เพราะได้เจอลูกชายเนี่ยนะ
That smile…
รอยยิ้มนั้น…
It's hard to believe that man was called the Vampire of Bavaria.
แทบไม่อยากจะเชื่อเลยว่าผู้ชายคนนั้น เคยมีฉายาว่าแวมไพร์แห่งบาวาเรีย
"I see. Johan is also here?" Is that so?
"อ้อเหรอ โยฮันก็มาด้วยงั้นเหรอ" มันใช่เหรอ
So, now you're running around looking for this puppy, huh?
ตอนนี้คุณก็เลยตามหาลูกหมาตัวนี้ไปทั่วเลยสินะ
Yes, it seems my client's ex-husband took off with it.
ใช่ครับ ดูเหมือนสามีเก่าของลูกค้าผม จะพามันไปด้วย
Looks like custody disputes over puppies can be difficult too.
ดูเหมือนการแย่งสิทธิ์ในการเลี้ยงดูลูกสุนัข ก็เป็นเรื่องยากเหมือนกันแฮะ
Good grief.
เหลือเชื่อจริงๆ
Sorry, but I'm going to have some wine.
ขอโทษนะ แต่ผมจะดื่มไวน์สักหน่อย
Go right ahead.
เอาเลยครับ
Water is enough for me.
ผมดื่มน้ำเปล่าก็พอแล้ว
You say work has slowed down,
เห็นคุณบอกว่างานคุณแย่ลง
but you also don't seem tempted by alcohol.
แต่คุณก็ไม่ได้ดูเหมือนอยากดื่มเหล้านะ
Yes, it's all okay on that front.
ครับ สำหรับเรื่องนั้นไม่มีปัญหาหรอกครับ
On that front?
เรื่องนั้นเหรอ
Is there something else bothering you then?
แปลว่ามีเรื่องอื่นที่คุณไม่สบายใจอยู่เหรอ
Well, I have some free time, so I end up doing stupid things.
ผมพอมีเวลาว่าง ก็เลยทำอะไรโง่ๆ น่ะครับ
Oh?
หา
I end up looking at personal scrapbooks I made in my police detective days.
ผมดูสมุดบันทึกส่วนตัว ที่ผมทำสมัยเป็นตำรวจสืบสวนน่ะครับ
About unsolved cases.
พวกคดีที่ยังคลี่คลายไม่ได้
I see.
เข้าใจแล้ว
And how do you feel when you look at them?
แล้วคุณรู้สึกยังไงเวลาที่ดูมันล่ะ
Frustrated.
หงุดหงิดครับ
With those murder cases and this one,
คดีฆาตกรรมพวกนั้น และคดีนี้
when I think about how those criminals are living comfortably in this world,
พอผมคิดว่าอาชญากรพวกนั้น กำลังอยู่อย่างสุขสบายบนโลกนี้
I just can't bear how incapable I am.
ผมก็ทนไม่ได้เลยที่ผมมันด้อยความสามารถ
You were capable.
คุณมีความสามารถนะ
But Richard, you'd get too caught up in your cases
แต่ริชาร์ด คุณจะติดอยู่ในคดีของคุณ
and identify too much with them.
และเห็นอกเห็นใจพวกเขามากเกินไปนะ
You'd get frustrated that you couldn't see what the culprit was thinking…
คุณจะหงุดหงิดที่คุณไม่เข้าใจว่าคนร้ายคิดอะไร…
So I ran to alcohol.
ผมเลยหันไปหาเหล้า
Yes, that's right.
ใช่ นั่นแหละ
Thank you for waiting.
ขอบคุณที่รอนะครับ
Hey, here's our food.
อ้าว อาหารมาแล้ว
But I don't think it's a bad thing
แต่ผมไม่คิดว่ามันเป็นเรื่องแย่นะ
that you look at scrapbooks from your old cases.
ที่คุณดูสมุดบันทึกคดีเก่าๆ ของคุณ
It just makes me more frustrated.
มันมีแต่ทำให้ผมหงุดหงิดมากขึ้นน่ะ
No, it's fine now.
ไม่หรอก ตอนนี้ไม่เป็นไรแล้วละ
Tell me what thoughts you have when you see them from your current perspective.
บอกผมหน่อยสิว่าคุณคิดยังไง เวลาที่คุณดูมันจากมุมมองปัจจุบัน
You were drunk and killed that young serial killer.
ตอนนั้นคุณเมาและทำให้ฆาตกรต่อเนื่องหนุ่มตาย
You are ready now to face that truth head on.
ตอนนี้คุณพร้อมที่จะเผชิญหน้ากับความจริงแล้ว
But you are still running away from
แต่คุณก็ยังคงวิ่งหนีจาก
remembering the thoughts you had when you pulled the trigger.
การนึกถึงความคิดที่คุณมีตอนที่คุณเหนี่ยวไก
You still see it, don't you?
คุณยังเห็นมันอยู่ใช่ไหม
That young man's ghost.
ผีของเด็กหนุ่มคนนั้นน่ะ
Yes.
ใช่ครับ
When you make everything clear and bring it all into the light,
เมื่อคุณทำให้ทุกอย่างชัดเจน และนำมันมาสู่แสงสว่างทั้งหมด
that ghost will disappear as well.
ผีตัวนั้นก็จะหายไปด้วย
"Bring it all into the light," huh?
"นำมันมาสู่แสงสว่างทั้งหมด" งั้นเหรอ
The Murder Case of Holmer the Accountant.
คดีฆาตกรรมโฮลเมอร์นักบัญชี
The victim, Joachim Holmer, had built a steady career,
เหยื่อชื่อโยอาคิม โฮลเมอร์ สร้างอาชีพการงานที่มั่นคง
and was not someone who would incur anyone's wrath.
และไม่ใช่คนที่จะทำให้ใครโกรธได้
Yet he was stabbed repeatedly and nothing was even stolen.
แต่เขาถูกกระหน่ำแทง และไม่มีข้าวของถูกขโมยไปสักชิ้น
The "Voice of God" Murder Case.
คดีฆาตกรรม "เสียงของพระเจ้า"
The victims were a former maid and chauffeur.
เหยื่อเป็นอดีตแม่บ้านและคนขับรถ
On the wall of both crime scenes,
บนผนังของทั้งสองที่เกิดเหตุ
the culprit scribbled a message. "I heard the voice of God."
คนร้ายเขียนข้อความไว้ว่า "ฉันได้ยินเสียงของพระเจ้า"
The Dornach CEO Murder Case.
คดีฆาตกรรมซีอีโอโดร์นาร์ค
Ruud Gauck, a prominent person of wealth in Bavaria,
รู้ด เกาค์ เศรษฐีที่มีชื่อเสียงในบาวาเรีย
was found dead in Hart-Holz forest.
ถูกพบเป็นศพอยู่ในป่าฮาร์ทโฮลซ์
The Spieler Couple Murder Case.
คดีฆาตกรรมคู่รักสปีเลอร์
A drowned middle-aged couple were found floating in the upper Isar River.
พบศพคู่รักวัยกลางคนที่จมน้ำตาย ลอยอยู่ในแม่น้ำอีซาร์ตอนบน
It is being investigated as one of the middle-aged couple serial murders.
มันถูกสอบสวนโดยจัดว่าเป็น หนึ่งในคดีฆาตกรรมต่อเนื่องคู่รักวัยกลางคน
The suspect, a Japanese doctor, is still at large.
ผู้ต้องสงสัยที่เป็นหมอชาวญี่ปุ่นยังคงลอยนวล
What a mess.
เละเทะจริงๆ
As the unsolved cases grew in number, so did my alcohol intake.
พอมีคดีที่ไขไม่ได้มากขึ้น ตอนนั้นฉันก็เลยดื่มเหล้ามากขึ้น
But now I'm different from back then.
แต่ตอนนี้ฉันไม่เหมือนตอนนั้นแล้ว
I see. It's as the doctor said.
เข้าใจแล้ว มันเป็นอย่างที่หมอพูด
So this is what he meant by thinking without drinking.
ที่เขาบอกว่าการคิดโดยไม่ดื่มมันเป็นแบบนี้นี่เอง
What?
เอ๊ะ
Hold on a second.
เดี๋ยวนะ
Think carefully.
พอมาคิดดีๆ
Think care--
พอมาคิด…
So?
ยังไงนะ
What was it that you remembered then?
ตอนนั้นคุณจำอะไรได้บ้าง
Well, that's the thing.
นั่นแหละประเด็น
Something did come to mind, but…
มีบางอย่างแวบเข้ามาในหัวผม แต่…
You saw that young man's ghost and your flash of inspiration vanished?
คุณเห็นผีของเด็กหนุ่มคนนั้น แล้วแรงดลใจที่เกิดขึ้นแวบนึงก็หายไปใช่ไหม
Yes.
ครับ
You needn't rush this.
คุณไม่ต้องรีบร้อนหรอก
That flash of inspiration will come to you again soon enough.
อีกไม่นานแรงดลใจที่เกิดขึ้น แวบนึงนั้นจะกลับมาหาคุณอีก
What was it that came to mind?
ตอนนั้นอะไรแวบเข้ามาในหัวฉันนะ
It felt like an important key to solving one of the unsolved cases.
รู้สึกเหมือนเป็นกุญแจสำคัญ ในการไขหนึ่งในคดีที่ยังไขไม่ได้เลย
Just my imagination.
ฉันแค่คิดไปเองแหละ
Who's there?
นั่นใครน่ะ
Who's there? Who's following me?
นั่นใครน่ะ ใครตามฉันมา
It's just like back then.
เหมือนตอนนั้นเลย
Back then, I was chasing him down in an alley like this…
ตอนนั้นฉันไล่ตามเขาไปในตรอกแบบนี้…
I'm sorry for visiting at this hour.
ขอโทษนะครับหมอ ที่มาหากลางดึก
No, you're ready to talk about everything.
ไม่เป็นไร คุณพร้อมจะพูดทุกเรื่องแล้วนี่
Let me hear it.
ว่ามาสิ
At that moment, I could see inside that young man.
ในตอนนั้น ผมมองเห็นในตัวเด็กหนุ่มคนนั้น
I learned that it existed in this world.
ผมได้เรียนรู้ว่ามันมีอยู่จริงในโลกนี้
True evil.
ปีศาจที่แท้จริง
That's why I…
ผมถึงได้…
That's why I shot down that young man.
ผมถึงได้ยิงเด็กหนุ่มคนนั้น
Good, you did well in telling me.
ดีมาก ดีแล้วที่คุณเล่าให้ผมฟัง
With this, you've really recovered.
แบบนี้แปลว่าคุณดีขึ้นแล้วจริงๆ
There's more.
ยังมีอีกครับ
I realized something.
ผมคิดอะไรบางอย่างได้
Yes?
อะไรเหรอ
What came to mind earlier…
สิ่งที่แวบเข้ามาในหัวผมก่อนหน้านี้…
All those unsolved cases that I had were actually
จริงๆ แล้วคดีที่ยังไขไม่ได้ทั้งหมดนั้นที่ผมเคยทำ
just one case.
เป็นแค่คดีเดียว
"Dear Dr. Gillen."
"ถึงหมอกิลเลน
"The book you sent me, Theory of Transcendent Criminal Psychology,
หนังสือทฤษฎีจิตวิทยาอาชญากรรม เหนือธรรมชาติที่คุณส่งมาให้ผม
was a fascinating read."
เป็นหนังสือที่ยอดเยี่ยมมาก
"I feel great joy in knowing that a pupil I taught
ผมดีใจมากที่ได้รู้ว่านักเรียนที่ผมเคยสอน
at  the University of Düsseldorf is actively working like this."
ที่มหาวิทยาลัยดึสเซิลดอร์ฟ ทำงานอย่างกระตือรือร้นแบบนี้
"By the way, Dr. Gillen,
ว่าแต่ หมอกิลเลน
in your interviews with Peter Jürgens, the serial killer you mentioned,
ที่คุณสัมภาษณ์ปีเตอร์ เยอร์เกนส์ ฆาตกรต่อเนื่องที่คุณพูดถึง
I believe he told you
ผมเชื่อว่าเขาบอกคุณว่า
that he was ordered by a friend to commit the murder."
เขาถูกเพื่อนคนนึงสั่งให้ลงมือฆาตกรรม
"My memory is unclear, so could you please tell me once more
ผมจำไม่ค่อยได้แล้ว คุณช่วยบอกผมอีกครั้งได้ไหม
the name of Jürgens's friend?"
ว่าเพื่อนของเยอร์เกนส์ชื่ออะไร
"P.S."
ป.ล.
"You were an incredibly brilliant student during your college years,
คุณเป็นนักเรียนที่เก่งมาก ในช่วงที่เรียนมหาวิทยาลัย
but you had a classmate
แต่คุณมีเพื่อนร่วมชั้นคนนึง
who was brilliant enough to compete with you for the top rank."
ที่เก่งพอจะแย่งที่หนึ่งกับคุณได้
"He continued on the path of becoming a brain surgeon,
เขาไปเรียนเป็นศัลยแพทย์ด้านสมองต่อ
but now he is the suspect of a serial murder case."
แต่ตอนนี้เขาเป็นผู้ต้องสงสัย ในคดีฆาตกรรมต่อเนื่อง
"Can you tell me whatever you know about him, however small it may be?"
ช่วยเล่าเรื่องเกี่ยวกับเขาให้ผมฟังหน่อยได้ไหม ไม่ว่าจะเรื่องเล็กน้อยแค่ไหนก็ตาม
"What kind of person is he,
เขาเป็นคนยังไง
and where is he now?"
และตอนนี้เขาอยู่ที่ไหน
"The man named Dr. Tenma."
ผู้ชายที่ชื่อหมอเท็นมะน่ะ"
Oh, you're the police detective from back then.
อ๋อ คุณตำรวจสายสืบตอนนั้นน่ะเอง
Well, now I'm a private investigator doing a variety of work.
ครับ ตอนนี้ผมเป็นนักสืบเอกชน ที่ทำงานหลากหลายแล้วละ
I apologize for bringing up such a tough topic,
ขอโทษที่พูดถึงเรื่องที่น่าลำบากใจนะครับ
but may I ask you one more time
แต่ผมขอถามคุณอีกครั้งได้ไหม
about the "Voice of God" Case where your mother was a victim?
เรื่องคดี "เสียงของพระเจ้า" ที่แม่คุณเป็นเหยื่อน่ะครับ
Of course.
ได้สิคะ
After all, it has already been four years, and the police are no longer trying.
ยังไงมันก็ผ่านมาสี่ปีแล้ว และตำรวจก็ไม่พยายามทำอะไรแล้วด้วย
Schuwald?
ชูวาลด์เหรอคะ
Yes.
ครับ
I believe your mother was a housekeeper for that wealthy individual.
ผมเชื่อว่าแม่คุณเคยเป็นแม่บ้านให้เศรษฐีคนนั้น
Yes, but that was 20 years ago.
ใช่ค่ะ แต่นั่นมันก็ 20 ปีมาแล้ว
Was there a reason why she quit?
เธอมีเหตุผลที่ลาออกรึเปล่าครับ
She wasn't in great health at the time,
ตอนนั้นแม่สุขภาพไม่ค่อยดีน่ะค่ะ
and she'd only take jobs in the neighborhood after that.
แล้วหลังจากนั้นแม่ก็รับงานแถวบ้านเท่านั้น
Could it be that things didn't go well with Mr. Schuwald?
เป็นไปได้ไหมว่ามีปัญหากับคุณชูวาลด์
That's unthinkable.
ไม่น่าเป็นไปได้หรอกค่ะ
In fact, she loved to read poems.
ที่จริง แม่ชอบอ่านบทกวีมากนะคะ
She said when Mr. Schuwald could still see,
แม่บอกว่าตอนที่คุณชูวาลด์ยังมองเห็น
they'd often read aloud together.
พวกเขาชอบอ่านบทกวีออกเสียงด้วยกัน
Oh, right. Please come this way.
จริงด้วย เชิญทางนี้สิคะ
See? Take a look.
เห็นไหมคะ ดูสิ
I've kept them, as they're memories of my mother.
ฉันเก็บมันไว้ เพราะมันเป็นความทรงจำของแม่ฉัน
All of these poetry anthologies
กวีนิพนธ์ทั้งหมดนี้
were presents she received from Mr. Schuwald.
เป็นของขวัญที่แม่ได้มาจากคุณชูวาลด์ค่ะ
The ex-detective who was on the Dornach CEO Murder Case
อดีตนักสืบที่ทำคดีฆาตกรรมซีอีโอโดร์นาร์ค
is now a private investigator, huh?
ตอนนี้เป็นนักสืบเอกชนงั้นเหรอ
I wanted to speak once more with you, the CEO's former secretary,
ผมอยากคุยกับคุณอีกครั้งครับ คุณอดีตเลขาของซีอีโอ
about people who resented your CEO.
เรื่องคนที่ไม่พอใจซีอีโอของคุณ
The CEO's enemies?
ศัตรูของซีอีโอเหรอ
I told you there'd be no end if I started listing them.
ผมบอกแล้วไงว่าให้พูดชื่อกี่วันก็ไม่หมดหรอก
The list of companies that went bankrupt because of the CEO, Mr. Gauck,
รายชื่อบริษัทที่เจ๊งเพราะคุณเกาค์ ซีอีโอของเรา
should already have been analyzed by the police long ago.
ตำรวจน่าจะทำการวิเคราะห์ไปนานแล้ว
There is one more influential wealthy individual in Bavaria, yes?
ยังมีเศรษฐีผู้มีอิทธิพลอีกคน ในบาวาเรียด้วยใช่ไหมครับ
What was his relationship with him?
เขาเป็นอะไรกับคนคนนั้นเหรอครับ
Do you mean Mr. Schuwald?
คุณหมายถึงคุณชูวาลด์เหรอ
Well, of course, they were life-long rivals.
แน่นอนว่าพวกเขาเป็นคู่แข่งกันมาตลอดชีวิต
Are you aware?
คุณรู้แล้วเหรอ
Of what?
อะไรครับ
Schuwald has gone bankrupt twice in the past.
ชูวาลด์เคยล้มละลายมาสองครั้ง
The second time was the result
ครั้งที่สองเป็นผลมาจาก
of fierce business competition with Mr. Gauck.
การแข่งขันทางธุรกิจที่ดุเดือดกับคุณเกาค์นี่แหละ
In other words, your CEO put Mr. Schuwald out of business.
พูดอีกอย่างก็คือ ซีอีโอของคุณทำให้คุณชูวาลด์ต้องเลิกกิจการ
But Schuwald has also put our CEO under before too.
แต่ชูวาลด์ก็เคยทำให้ซีอีโอของเรา เจ๊งมาก่อนเหมือนกัน
Did they despise each other?
พวกเขาเกลียดกันไหมครับ
Of course.
แน่นอน
There'd be trouble when the two met occasionally at party venues,
บางครั้งจะมีปัญหา เวลาที่ทั้งสองคนเจอกันตามงานเลี้ยง
baring their emotions as they'd quarrel with each other.
พวกเขาทะเลาะกันอย่างดุเดือดเลยละ
Those two did that?
สองคนนั้นทำแบบนั้นเหรอ
Yes, despite their cold nature.
ใช่ ทั้งที่ปกติเป็นคนไร้อารมณ์มาก
They could argue with nobody on an equal footing but each other.
พวกเขาทะเลาะกันโดยที่ไม่มีใครดีไปกว่าใคร
Rather than rivals,
พวกเขาเป็นยิ่งกว่าศัตรู
they were actually more like friends.
จริงๆ แล้วพวกเขาเหมือนเป็นเพื่อนกันมากกว่า
Careful up there!
ระวังหน่อยสิ
Yeah, he knew Hans very well.
ใช่ เขารู้จักฮันส์ดีมาก
He was one of the two people killed in the "Voice of God" Case.
เขาเป็นหนึ่งในสองคน ที่ถูกฆ่าในคดี "เสียงของพระเจ้า"
He was a good guy too. I feel sorry for him.
เขาเป็นคนดีด้วยนะ ผมสงสารเขาจริงๆ
Was Hans really that nice?
ฮันส์เป็นคนดีขนาดนั้นเลยเหรอครับ
Yeah, he'd treat him to drinks often.
ใช่ เขาเลี้ยงเหล้าผมบ่อยเลยละ
He used to work as Schuwald's chauffeur, right?
เขาเคยทำงานเป็นคนขับรถ ของชูวาลด์ใช่ไหมครับ
Apparently.
เหมือนจะใช่นะ
But that was 30 years ago.
แต่นั่นมันเมื่อ 30 ปีก่อนโน้น
Do you know why he was fired?
รู้ไหมครับว่าทำไมเขาถึงโดนไล่ออก
It's because Schuwald went bankrupt around then.
เพราะช่วงนั้นชูวาลด์ล้มละลายน่ะ
Oh, I see.
อ่อ เข้าใจแล้วครับ
So it's not like there were any other issues?
งั้นก็ไม่ใช่ว่ามีปัญหาอื่นใช่ไหมครับ
Listen up.
ฟังนะ
I'm saying this to protect Hans's honor.
ผมจะพูดแบบนี้เพื่อปกป้องเกียรติของฮันส์นะ
It didn't matter if you were a rich bastard or a poor person like us.
ไม่สำคัญว่าคุณจะเป็นคนรวย หรือเป็นคนจนอย่างเรา
He was a good guy who'd hang out with you no matter who you are.
แต่เขาเป็นคนดีที่จะคบหากับคุณ ไม่ว่าคุณจะเป็นใคร
He'd often say
เขามักจะพูดว่า
that he was the one who taught the rich guy how to birdwatch.
เขาเป็นคนสอนคนรวยให้ดูนก
Birdwatch?
ดูนกเหรอ
Yeah. He may be called a vampire, but when he took him to the woods,
ใช่ ชูวาลด์อาจมีฉายาว่าแวมไพร์ แต่เวลาฮันส์พาเขาไปป่านะ
he'd get excited like a little boy.
เขาจะตื่นเต้นเหมือนเด็กน้อยเลยละ
Two years have already passed,
ผ่านไปสองปีแล้ว
yet whenever I think of my husband, I still…
แต่เมื่อไหร่ที่ฉันคิดถึงสามีฉัน ฉันก็ยัง…
My husband was an earnest man.
สามีฉันเป็นคนเอาจริงเอาจัง
There was no reason people would hold a grudge against him.
ไม่มีเหตุผลเลยที่ใครจะโกรธแค้นเขา
Yet he was killed in such a manner…
แต่เขาก็ถูกฆ่าแบบนั้น…
I can only imagine.
ผมพอเข้าใจครับ
I apologize, but I believe your husband was…
ต้องขอโทษด้วยนะครับ แต่ผมเชื่อว่าสามีคุณ…
Yes, he was in an orphanage as a child.
ใช่ค่ะ ตอนเด็กๆ เขาอยู่บ้านเด็กกำพร้า
He moved from one foster home to another
เขาย้ายบ้านอุปถัมภ์หลายแห่ง
and became an accountant after all that hardship.
และมาเป็นนักบัญชีได้หลังจากลำบากมามาก
Mr. Schuwald asked him to work as his accountant, yes?
คุณชูวาลด์เคยชวนเขา ไปเป็นนักบัญชีใช่ไหมครับ
Yes, many times.
ใช่ค่ะ หลายครั้งเลย
But he would refuse.
แต่เขาก็ปฏิเสธ
Not only was he busy with the work he had,
ไม่ใช่แค่เพราะเขางานยุ่งอยู่แล้วนะคะ
but he said his philosophy regarding money was different from his own.
แต่เขาบอกว่าหลักการเรื่องเงินของชูวาลด์ ต่างจากหลักการของเขาด้วย
My husband was adamant that the money be clean.
สามีฉันยืนกรานว่าเงินจะต้องสะอาด
Thank you for your cooperation.
ขอบคุณที่ให้ความร่วมมือนะครับ
Will the culprit be caught?
จะจับคนร้ายได้ไหมคะ
I'll do my best.
ผมจะทำสุดความสามารถครับ
I will catch him no matter what.
ผมจะจับเขาให้ได้ไม่ว่ายังไงก็ตาม
Goodbye.
สวัสดีครับ
-Oh, by the way… -Yes?
- อ่อ ว่าแต่… - คะ
Do you know how your husband met him?
คุณรู้ไหมว่าสามีคุณเจอเขาได้ยังไง
Oh, he said they met in the woods.
อ๋อ เขาบอกว่าเจอกันครั้งแรกในป่าค่ะ
In the woods?
ในป่าเหรอ
It was when Mr. Schuwald could still see.
ตอนนั้นคุณชูวาลด์ยังมองเห็นอยู่เลยค่ะ
He ran into him in the woods.
เขาบังเอิญเจอคุณชูวาลด์ในป่า
Why was it in a place like that?
ทำไมถึงเป็นที่แบบนั้นนะ
They were birdwatching.
พวกเขาไปดูนกค่ะ
They met many times after that.
พวกเขาเจอกันหลายครั้งหลังจากนั้น
Birdwatching…
การดูนก…
Excited like a little boy…
ตื่นเต้นเหมือนเด็กน้อย…
They'd read aloud together…
พวกเขาอ่านออกเสียงด้วยกัน…
Friends…
เพื่อน…
Are you okay?!
เป็นอะไรรึเปล่า
Yes, I'm fine. Thank you.
ไม่เป็นไรครับ ขอบคุณ
What awful driving.
ขับรถแย่ชะมัด
It almost looked like he was trying to hit you.
แทบจะเหมือนเขาพยายามจะชนคุณเลย
Dr. Reichwein, I've collected all the evidence.
หมอไรช์ไวน์ครับ ผมรวบรวมหลักฐานทั้งหมดได้แล้วครับ
It was exactly as I told you the other day.
มันเป็นอย่างที่ผมบอกหมอเมื่อวันก่อนเป๊ะเลยครับ
The many cases I had when I was a police detective
หลายคดีที่ผมทำตอนเป็นตำรวจสายสืบ
were all pointing in the same direction.
ชี้ไปในทิศทางเดียวกันทั้งหมด
The "Voice of God" Murder Case.
คดีฆาตกรรม "เสียงของพระเจ้า"
The Dornach CEO Murder Case.
คดีฆาตกรรมซีอีโอโดร์นาร์ค
The Accountant Murder Case.
คดีฆาตกรรมนักบัญชี
At first glance, these cases seem unrelated to each other.
มองแวบแรก คดีพวกนี้ดูไม่เกี่ยวกันเลย
The modus operandi are all different too.
วิธีการลงมือของคนร้ายก็ไม่เหมือนกัน
The victims aren't connected
เหยื่อไม่ได้เกี่ยวข้องกัน
and they're not related monetarily in any way either.
และพวกเขาก็ไม่เกี่ยวข้องกับเรื่องเงินเลยด้วย
Thus, there was one truth that didn't exist on record.
แต่มีความจริงข้อนึงที่ไม่ได้บันทึกไว้
There was one point that connected them all.
มีจุดหนึ่งที่เชื่อมโยงพวกเขาทั้งหมดเข้าด้วยกัน
Each victim's death
การตายของเหยื่อแต่ละราย
forced Schuwald into solitude.
ทำให้ชูวาลด์ต้องอยู่อย่างโดดเดี่ยว
And there was one more strange commonality.
และยังมีลักษณะร่วมแปลกๆ อีกอย่างนึงด้วย
In the Dornach CEO Murder Case,
ในคดีฆาตกรรมซีอีโอโดร์นาร์ค
right before the crime,
ก่อนเกิดเหตุฆาตกรรม
Mr. Gauck left, saying he was going to an important business meeting.
คุณเกาค์ออกไปข้างนอก บอกว่าจะไปประชุมสำคัญ
The name of the person he was to meet,
ชื่อของคนที่เขาจะไปพบ
and the name of the god written on the walls in the "Voice of God" Case.
และชื่อของพระเจ้าที่เขียนไว้ บนผนังในคดี "เสียงของพระเจ้า"
And the middle-aged couple serial murder,
และคดีฆาตกรรมต่อเนื่องคู่รักวัยกลางคน
the only case that seemed unrelated to the other cases I had.
คดีเดียวที่ดูเหมือนไม่เกี่ยวข้อง กับคดีอื่นๆ ที่ผมเคยทำเลย
The culprit's name that was stated during the investigation by a suspect,
ชื่อที่หมอชาวญี่ปุ่นที่เป็นผู้ต้องสงสัย
the Japanese doctor.
ระบุว่าเป็นคนร้าย
They were all the same name.
ทั้งหมดเป็นชื่อเดียวกัน
Johan.
โยฮัน
A former pupil of mine, a criminal psychologist,
อดีตลูกศิษย์ผมที่เป็นนักจิตวิทยาอาชญากรรม
was researching a serial killer who was ordered by a friend to kill.
กำลังทำการวิจัยฆาตกรต่อเนื่อง ที่ถูกเพื่อนสั่งให้ฆ่าคน
He told me of this in his letter.
เขาบอกเรื่องนี้กับผมในจดหมายของเขา
The name of that friend was also
ชื่อของเพื่อนที่สั่งให้ฆ่าก็ชื่อ
Johan.
โยฮัน
It's a common name.
มันเป็นชื่อเดียวกัน
The connection between the cases is nothing more than a guess.
ความเชื่อมโยงระหว่างคดีต่างๆ ไม่ได้เป็นแค่การคาดเดา
But if this is indeed the truth,
แต่ถ้านี่เป็นเรื่องจริง
it would mean this Johan strategically committed serial murders
ก็แปลว่าโยฮันคนนี้ ทำการฆาตกรรมต่อเนื่องอย่างมีกลยุทธ์
for the past four years to push Schuwald into total isolation.
มาตลอดสี่ปีเพื่อทำให้ชูวาลด์โดดเดี่ยวจริงๆ
And Margot Langer, the one who birthed Schuwald's son, is conveniently dead.
และมาร์โกต์ แลงเกอร์ ผู้ให้กำเนิด ลูกชายของชูวาลด์ก็ตายไปแล้ว
The student, Fahren, who claimed to be Schuwald's son,
นักศึกษาชื่อฟาห์เรน ที่เคยอ้างว่าเป็นลูกชายของชูวาลด์
conveniently killed himself when the real son appeared.
ก็ฆ่าตัวตายซะเฉยๆ เมื่อลูกชายตัวจริงปรากฏตัว
If he really does exist,
ถ้าโยฮันมีตัวตนจริง
where is this Johan now?
ตอนนี้เขาอยู่ที่ไหนนะ
I see. Johan is also here?
อ้อเหรอ โยฮันก็มาด้วยงั้นเหรอ
Hi, Johan. What lovely weather we have today.
ไง โยฮัน วันนี้อากาศดีมากเลยเนอะ
Yes, it's very nice.
ใช่ครับ อากาศดีมาก
He's right next to Schuwald.
เขาอยู่ใกล้ๆ ชูวาลด์นั่นแหละ